when you were born through the birth canal
countless bacteria covered your body
they'll be with you throughout your life
if you were born by caesarian section
you're more likely to develop asthma
or immune diseases
our mother's breast milk contains a special sugar
that feeds specific microbial species
which help regulate our immune system
it generally
takes two years for a Newborn to develop a complete
healthy microbiome
each person's microbiome is unique
they come from your phone
to your hands and then all over your body
even inside your mouth is full of them
yet we have little control over them
for millions of years
humans made a pact with these microbes
we provide food and shelter
and in return they work for us